



Kaspars Upenieks

• Address: 13 Cleveland Drive, OX4 3HA, Oxford, United Kingdom

Email address: kasparsupenieks@gmail.com

○ Whatsapp Messenger: +447856678878

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/public-profile/in/kaspars-upenieks-34a6b4102/

Gender: Male **Date of birth:** 16/11/1993 **Nationality:** Latvian

ABOUT ME

I am a highly competent data warehouse software developer with 6-year experience developing a wide range of data warehouse/ETL/SQL solutions. But from all my experience in Computer Science I have understood that area which I would like the most is web development. That is why I am currently looking for a job as a web developer and meanwhile building my skills related to web development were I already have solid HTML, CSS and JavaScript knowledge.

WORK EXPERIENCE

[01/12/2014 - 01/03/2015] Internship as Android Developer

Emergn

City: Riga

Country: Latvia

Main activities and responsibilities:

Working in a team of 3-5 programmers on Android mobile software application development, which included working with Android legacy codebase and version control to achieve higher team productivity. As well as developing new Android widgets that were capable of communicating with the current software application. The achieved result was Android base software application that was used in the company's conference rooms, completely capable of displaying work schedules, temperature, current time and other customizable widgets. Furthermore, Agile methodology documentation of the project was made, to describe project functions and requirement implementation.

[02/03/2015 - Current] **Programmer/ETL Developer**

Emergn

City: Riga **Country:** Latvia

Business or sector: Information and communication

Main activities and responsibilities:

Working with Latvian State revenue department data warehouse Agile/Kanban team. Main responsibility is implementing ETL solutions in an existing data warehouse using SAP BODS, IBM DataStage and Pentaho ETL tools. As a result, additional skills like ODBC, JDBC connections and SQL in different database systems(MS SQL, Informix, Sybase, Oracle, Netezza) were adapted.

Other projects include:

- SAP HANA,
- Jira/Git/GitHub version control,
- Web development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript),
- Java SE(clients),
- System analytics,
- · Code supervision,
- Web Services(SOAP, REST)
- Scripting languages.

Work outcome: Client is provided with functioning schedulable ETL processes and other software for data warehouse with full software development cycle support to make better business decisions.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

$[\ 01/09/2017 - 27/06/2019\]$ Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

University of Latvia

Address: Riga, Latvia Final grade: First

Main subject / occupational skills covered:

Formal grammatic; Databases; Computer graphics and image processing; Mathematical logic; Linux system programming; IT project management; CKAN framework and structured data usage in web.

[01/09/2013 - 02/07/2015] First Professional degree in Computer Programming\Programmer

University of Latvia

Address: Riga, Latvia

Main subject / occupational skills covered:

C++ programming; Web development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Laravel, NodeJS); Computer-system administration (LAMP, WAMP); Mathematics (Discrete mathematics, Mathematical analytics, Analytic geometry); Databases (MS Sql); Computer-system architecture; Software Engineering.

Mother tongue(s): Latvian

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

Russian

LISTENING C1 READING C2 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

PROJECTS

[01/01/2021 - Current] Web development

Being more than 5 years in industry I have realized that web development is the main area where I have interest. At start I started to do some little tasks and projects in HTML,CSS and JavaScript, but in 2021 decided to take it more seriously and learn it as mush as I can, currently I have finished freecodecamp.org "Responsive web design", "Java Script Algorithms and Data Structures" certifications and have solid knowledge on main Front-end development technologies: HTML,CSS and JavaScript. Now learning some more advanced JavaScript topics and getting myself into Frameworks like node.js and React and slowly building up my portfolio:https:\\www.kasparsupenieks.id.lv.

Data transformation\ETL jobs

Main area of my daily work. Creating different data transformation jobs using SAP BODS(biggest expertise), Pentaho, IBM Datastage products and different databases like Netezza, Sybase IQ, SAP HANA, Oracle, IBM Informix, MS SQL. All of those products were mainly designed for Latvian State revenue department data warehouse purposes.

Open data project for Latvian state revenue department

This project consistent of three main parts:

- -Report export from SAP Restful framework using Java client;
- -ETL development using SAP BODS;
- -Data Upload with Java client for CKAN framework.

In result i created data transformation job which can be scheduled and extracts data from SAP Bussines Object reports and uploads data on Latvian government open data portal data.gov.lv

Other projects

Other project include using different technology for alternate solutions, like creating different clients in Java SE, Python or doing some machine learning basic tasks.

HOBBIES AND INTER-ESTS

Interests

After computer science field I could say that my other passion is finance/economic. In high school years participated in many Latvian and Baltic economic competitions and currently actively invest in stock market.

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Communication\organisational skills

Good communication and organisational skills gained through my experience working in IT field with different teams of 2-10 people. Also working in Kanban methodology team with daily stand-ups and different version control\work reporting systems.

OTHER

Jobe related courses\skills

- e-Guardion and ECDL Computer skills sertificate BDA
- JAVA SE 8 Fundamentals Diploma from Oracle University
- ∘ Java SE 8 Fundamentals Ed 1 Sertificate
- FreeCodeCamp.org "Responsive Web Design" certification
- FreeCodeCamp.org "JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures" certification